Discover the true story of one of America's
brightest stars... that faded too soon.
Selena is a drama, music, history film directed by Gregory Nava.
In this biographical drama, Selena Quintanilla is born into
a musical Mexican-American family in Texas.
Her father, Abraham, realizes that his young daughter is talented
and begins performing with her at small venues.
She finds success and falls for her guitarist, Chris
Perez, who draws the ire of her father.
Seeking mainstream stardom, Selena begins recording an
English-language album which, tragically, she would never complete.
Selena Quintanilla, played by Jennifer Lopez.
Suzette Quintanilla, played by Jackie Guerra.
Marcela Quintanilla, played by Constance Marie.
Sara, played by Alex Meneses.
Chris Perez, played by Jon Seda.
Abraham Quintanilla, played by Edward James Olmos.
Selena is a 1997 American biographical musical drama film about Tejano
music star Selena Quintanilla-Pérez, played by Jennifer Lopez.
The film, written and directed by Gregory Nava, chronicles the star's rise to fame
and death when she was murdered by Yolanda Saldívar at the age of 23.
In addition to Lopez, the film also stars Edward James Olmos, Jon Seda, Constance
Marie, Jacob Vargas, Lupe Ontiveros, and Jackie Guerra in her film debut.
Selena was released in the United States on March 21, 1997, by Warner Bros.
The film received positive reviews from critics and grossed $35 million
worldwide against a production budget of $20 million.
For her performance, Jennifer Lopez received a Best Actress
nomination at the 55th Golden Globe Awards.
In 2021, it was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically,
or aesthetically significant", and was re-released in select cinemas on April 7, 2022, to coincide with the film's 25th anniversary.
In 2024, the Pérez Art Museum Miami organized a screening of Selena as part
of the institution's Floating Films with Ballyhoo Media.
During this event, the film was screened from the water.
The film explores themes of texas, biography, elopement, bustier, fan club.
The tone is emotional.